

Caitlin Gilbert

PhD Candidate in Neuroscience with expertise in neurobiology, data science, science writing and communication. My thesis aims to understand the genetic underpinnings of speech/language acquisition. For this work I have developed skillsets in data mining, statistical modeling, machine learning, and visualization.

¥ () in

New York City, NY caitlinsgilbert@gmail.com

Work Experience

Rockefeller University, PhD Student, Sep 2015 - Present

- Study songbirds to understand the epigenetic basis of speech and language acquisition
- Developed novel bioinformatic pipelines to study genomic signatures of the songbird brain
- Apply data science tools including visualization, data wrangling, and statistical analysis to understand phenomena and communicate research findings

Pete for America, Data Team Lead, Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

- Developed the Digital Captains data team's strategy to maximize PFA's online engagement and outreach across social media platforms
- Built pipelines to aggregate social media data, perform engagement analytics, and to visualize engagement across platforms
- Led team of 50+ volunteers in implementing data strategy for the Digital Captains program
- Created database for a novel canvassing program ("Digital Door Knocking") based on public Twitter data of online supporters

Harvard Medical School, Research Assistant, Jun 2013 - Jun 2015

• Worked on potential treatment for Rett Syndrome and studied its underlying genetic mechanisms

The Kinetix Group, Project Manager, Jan 2013 - Apr 2013

• Led student consultants in a deep-dive analysis of healthcare insurance exchanges, specifically in the context of the PP-ACA, and created multidisciplinary final deliverables that incorporated design, writing, research, and oral presentation expertise

NextGen Journal, Writer, Sep 2010 - Dec 2012

• Wrote feature articles exploring the wide variety of behaviors and trends typical of modern youth culture and the neurobiological and psychological foundations behind them

The Hoya Newspaper, Writer/Columnist, Nov 2009 - Dec 2011

• Wrote biweekly column exploring the underlying neurobiological and psychological bases for common human behaviors, providing thorough scientific perspectives of issues relevant to college students

Education

- Rockefeller University, Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Neuroscience, 2015 2021
- Georgetown University, Bachelor of Science (BS), Neurobiology, 2009 2013

Skills

Programming languages: R, Bash

Software: Adobe Illustrator/Photoshop, Microsoft Office, Google Suite

Specializations: Statistical Analysis, Science Writing, Neuroscience, Bioinformatics